[Music]
so hope you're having a good time at the
conference for our last session today uh
we have Mr bhagavadas Gupta mdn CEO of
icic Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited the largest private sector
General Insurance company in India Mr
Das guptas began his career with the
Earth while ICICI limited 1992 and he's
held key leadership positions in diverse
business areas in the ICICI group
including project Finance corporate
banking e-commerce and Technology
Management International Banking and
life insurance
he is currently the chairman of Vicky's
insurance and pension committee and is a
member of IDR irdra Insurance advisory
committee
uh he'll be discussing the evolution of
industrial insurance industry and the
roadmap to drive profitable growth for
icsa Lombard the discussion will be held
with the Avinash who leads our insurance
desk and then we'll have question and
answer on answers after that thank you a
lot for agreeing to attend our
conference and to have this session
uh to start off with I mean particularly
in the context of insurance and General
Insurance that's the business of purely
risk uh you have three broad set of
stakeholders uh one of course your
policyholders at the heart of everything
and then you have shareholders and your
employee and distributors
and it's really for an insurer it's a
tough task sort of balancing the
interest of uh the three I mean because
often more than not you will be hearing
one complaining about their sort of
interesting ignored so in your
experience of over decades how have you
I mean sort of a managed to balance the
interest of Siri and if compared to any
sort of your other industry or your
other experience how difficult is it in
insurance
so thank you good afternoon everyone and
uh this is not a question that I expect
you to get in this conference in a
management you know consultant meeting
maybe yes this is a good question to ask
but let me uh kind of think about this
and um you see you know in any business
there are multiple stakeholders in
insurance I think the incremental
very important stakeholder from a
financial service perspective is a
distributor because insurance is a
product that is typically distributed
through third third party entities
but let's step back and think about
creating value in a in a business right
so at the end of the day if you want to
create value
um at the end of the day you have to
provide some value to customers
so at least the lens that we look at
whenever we take a final decision
whenever all forces are aligned there's
no issue whenever there's a conflict uh
I think the final uh you know vote goes
in favor of the customer uh and and and
that is our views that's the only way to
build a sustainable business when you
look at the employee you know at the end
of the day you obviously have to invest
in your employees but as long as the
employees objective is aligned to the
organization in terms of creating value
for the customer I don't see a problem
now coming back to your question about
shareholders
obviously at the end of the day if you
do not
you know have a franchise that you're
building where there is some kind of a
moat and you are building something of
value over the period uh your
shareholders will not benefit so now
let's look at the your three
stakeholders so there are situations
where the insurance distributor may want
to extract maximum value out of out of a
transaction that's true that does happen
but if you study Global Insurance
markets
while that may be the case but even the
distributor understands that if finally
if you want to you know build your
business build scale it has to be
reasonable in terms of what is it that
uh ux extract in terms of the value
what does happen in an immature market
like in India and I call it a immature
Market because uh while it's 22 years I
think the practices still are evolving
what does happen in the mature markets
is that there are companies which at
times want to uh you know gain market
share at the cost of the shareholder and
in that in those situation the
distributor benefits
ah finally you know with the customer
benefits or not the distribution benefit
distributed benefits so it's a question
of the market maturity
um when people realize that if you want
to create a franchise you want to create
a create a business model which lasts
you have to think about how are you
returning you know you're providing
enough returns returns to your
shareholders and India we've seen many
phases we've seen the opening up in in
the initial days when it was a tariff
Market uh you know things were much
better then you saw a whole stream of
companies coming in around the 2007 to
2012-13 Mark 2011-12 and there was a lot
of aggression which kind of died down
towards the end of 2018-19 and again you
had another you know another round of
aggression largely because a lot of
capital coming in and the capital was
valuing business uh with a multiple
which is unique to India which anywhere
in the world people will laugh at which
is price to gwp now price to gwp can
never be a multiple to value insurance
company but unfortunately investors in
India do so whenever you see companies
valued at price to gwp obviously people
will chase growth for At Any cost at
which time you will pay whatever com you
know commission that you want to pay to
the distributor for growth which is
obviously not a sustainable model so you
have to think about uh the the the three
legs have to align in a manner that the
this tool on which you're sitting is
stable
okay uh so I was about to go to uh maybe
segmental but because you have raised a
very pertinent point of again Capital
chasing uh the growth and that's why
I've again uh I'm sort of bringing this
question forward uh I mean over the last
five seven years there was some kind of
at least I would say slow uh slow down
in numbers of companies or like a stable
number because I mean they were already
I would say too many or competition was
uh but again we are seeing our new
licenses uh being applied for uh new
licenses are granted and companies again
entering uh so at the juncture when we
were hoping that okay at least uh uh you
know the capital providers are realizing
that it is not easy to sort of a
generate return on Capital in this
business uh it is not so easy as you
rightly say that the multiples like
price to zwp it started to vanish but
again we are seeing that some sort of so
how do you see sort of a competitive
landscape or say over next 35 previous
I think we are seeing a lot of talk
about new capacity or new entities
coming in I am not really seeing any
genuine
serious player coming in in the next
couple of years
what I mean by that is that as I said
there's a lot of players who we all know
are interested applied Etc but I don't
see too many of them with Deep Pockets
and with this the right kind of investor
base to compete in the market in the
next couple of years so let's look at
the players who may come in if let's say
there is a global MNC which comes in
with a 74 stake in a entity I don't
think you should worry about because
India is a very very under penetrated
marketing if you look at let's say 32
companies in this market of this size
and opportunity it's not a big number
uh but and I'm using that as an example
because these typically are more
responsible Capital right they
understand insurance and they build want
to build Insurance in a sensible manner
I don't think you should worry about it
if you are seeing the similar type of
capital that was coming in or was
interested about four or five years back
which was uh you know grow at any cost I
will fund you for five six years and
find the next buyer to take me out I
think that is a that would be a cause
for concern as but as of now I think
even that capital is beginning to
realize that it's not very easy to
create value in insurance through that
model so I'm you know maybe a year back
I was a bit more concerned about a lot
more Capital coming in but right now I'm
not as concerned
I think what has happened in the last
two to three years is people have seen
the uh you know implications people have
also made some calls on certain product
segments and when we get into get into
products we can talk about that and I I
think people are beginning to realize
that those calls may not have been a
sensible call so I'm not as concerned
about at least in the next couple of
years about too much of capital which is
changing growth at any cost coming into
the market
that nice to hear that the market is
going to show some discipline uh you
again brought a point regarding under
penetration and particularly in the
context of General Insurance it becomes
very very more imperative than life
because in context of life you have
competing savings and investment
products but here you are in the
business of purely risk that either I
mean the risk is covered or it's not
covered now I mean over the last 20
years or you have multiple uh sort of a
lacks of growth started with motor then
came crop over the last five seven years
Health has been the key driver
but one thing that I I mean still I
would say a highly under penetrated that
is what in the oversea market they call
it home insurance in Indian context I
mean we have fire or like engineering
that is largely a wholesale in the
retail context home insurance I mean for
earthquake fires or like theft it's
almost I mean buying mortgages is almost
a kind of a negligible now what are the
challenges I mean particularly because
our housing market is also not that
organized so what are the challenges you
are sort of a the industry has faced and
you in this backdrop of what is
happening particularly The increased
National calamities uh do you see that I
mean uh this home insurance can pick up
or become meaningful over sort of a
medium term and if there is any sort of
a policy tweak or support that
government need to do
I think that's a great question and
before I answer that I'll just spend two
minutes talking about or building on the
point that he first made that GI is very
different from Li uh we both have the
moniker insurance but honestly I think
our businesses are chalk and cheese and
I think the beauty of GI is the fact
that in financial services
our space is not computed by any other
player so in life they have a mutual
fund for saving this banking for us it's
a pure risk business and that's I think
the uniqueness and the beauty of our
business uh to respond to your specific
question I think
um
I think multiple reason why it's not
picked up
um one is mindsets uh you know you know
and we used to see the same thing with
health maybe over 10 years back no one
worried about uh have you know needing a
health insurance health insurance was a
massively a pushed product today A lot
has changed right in terms of awareness
and understanding that for the need for
health insurance the same is the story
with home insurance today the mindset is
that you know burglary cat doesn't it
happens to you not to me so I don't
worry about it that's number one number
two uh I think as an industry we've not
designed products
with a retail customer in mind it's
largely a cut piece of the corporate
product which is you know tariff wording
standard terms and conditions which is
also changing now with the with the
deterification and the use and file
regulation that has come in
in terms of policy support so so just to
conclude the thought process so I think
the awareness is also changing as you
rightly said you know there is lot more
awareness of catastrophes the frequency
of cats have increased
um and people are now going to innovate
on product category so I think the home
insurance piece will pick up but can it
pick up to the level that it or will it
pick up to the level that it can the
answer in my sense is no it will it will
still maybe grow at 30 35 but it's not
reaching the opportunity or the
potential that it has and one policy
support that we as an industry have been
talking about is I mean everyone keeps
talking about tax Etc I think we should
not expect that it's very clear where
the government is headed in terms of
simplification of tax structures and
exemptions so I don't expect that and
and I think it's correct that the
direction that we are moving in the on
the direct tax side so one uh you know
other intervention that we've been
seeking is that
when an asset is insured let's say for a
banker the underlying risk comes down so
one of the requests that the you know
industry has made to our regulator and
you know we I I understand The
Regulators they end up with the banking
regulator is that there should be some
kind of a capital relief if there's an
insurance uh you know for a home loan
for example it's a fair ask it's a
reasonable ask and it's good for
everyone concerned
it will help the bankers and it will
help the insurance industry and it will
help the the the the policy holder if
that happens that will be a positive
oh uh right so I mean you are hopeful
that it will pick up but still not at
the level seen in the Western Market it
will take some time here
okay now uh moving on a bit to the
Regulatory and uh I mean governance or
developments so one of course I mean
there have been a kind of over planned
overhaul of insurance bill that is I
mean right now it has not come in this
station of parliament but there have
been a lot of talk around at least the
idea of composite now if we were to look
I mean around globally our composite is
a concept has not been that great in
large Market at least markets comparable
to our size so in Indian context If This
Were to come or I mean uh what's your
thought on I mean uh you know the
success of that composite insurer and
sort of a challenges or for any new
licensing coming as a composite insurer
and if that were to become reality
how sort of it puts uh the general
insurer versus life insurer because
there is a sort of a lot of talk around
health insurance piece particularly and
the advantage or life insurance
companies have in terms of distribution
yeah so I think that's a key point that
you're making I think we're trying to
find a solution to a problem in a
certain approach whether it's a West
approach or not time will tell
um so the problem that we're trying to
solve is that in the category of Health
there is a clear demarcation of between
the non-life and the life segment and
that's and since we've not found a
solution that is up to uh you know the
expectation of some one stakeholder so
we are trying to find a uh a new
solution now now let's go to the core
issue the core issue is that health
insurance Indemnity health insurance
shortail you know short-term products
are the domain of the non-life companies
in the sahis and the long-term uh
policies of the domain of the life
companies so till I think 2015 this
wasn't the case 2014 I think it was 14
or 15 it was changed till that time it
was not the case and at that point in
time also if you see uh almost 95
percent the indemnity Health was sold by
the non-life companies and I'll explain
why uh and and I'll then hopefully
answer answer your questions more
specifically so if you look at health
Health indemnity
almost 50 percent of the business comes
from Group Health which is I'm talking
about the employer you know policies
group mediclaim or group health
insurance which is what corporates
provide their employees
now there I don't think the retail
distribution of Life plays any role it
is largely an advantage of the GI
companies because you are providing a
bouquet of offerings to a corporate
fire Marine liability you know
engineering and also health so there you
don't have a real play uh you know as a
life company the second part which is
the retail Indemnity distribution which
is distributed through uh agency I think
there is obviously a distribution play
well that's largely been kind of taken
away by the sahis because they have a
regulatory Arbitrage where they can just
walk up to your agent and sign him up
without having to license them
so the distribution is already happening
whoever is interested in distributing
Health Indemnity is already Distributing
it through his may not be through the
life companies
the other aspect of Health you know
insurance is that Beyond distribution
there are certain other core
capabilities that you need which is
unlike life insurance the frequency of
claims is much higher you have to build
capability on that service angle uh you
have the network management piece you
have the fraud waste and abuse which is
a very typical very typical issue for
for health insurance not just here
globally so you have to build those
capabilities so just by unifying the two
licenses you may solve the distribution
problem but you don't necessarily solve
this problem having said that people may
come together and maybe a life company
will buy you a sahi there are maybe four
or five of them and come together and
and build this business which is fine I
mean I don't see a see an issue with
that
coming to your larger point on
globally what we've seen we know them
are you know in large markets even
companies which has both entities have
kept it separate right because and
there's a fundamental reason for it
because as we discuss life insurance and
GI is chocolate is very very different
business very different risks that
you're managing very different
accounting principles very different
Horizon of investment all of those are
very different so even if you combine
the two entities I think the only thing
that you're leveraging is the
distribution rest of it you have to
manage the two pieces very very
differently so it is possible that
you'll get a life and health company as
a as a combo entity uh
may not be as many Life Health GI going
ahead but we'll have to see and honestly
at this point in time I'm sure all of us
are evaluating what is the best model
for us
um but this doesn't seem to be around
the corner so whenever that happens we
will uh decide what's the best approach
so one more question before we go to the
audiences uh slightly more than five
years post your listing and of course
you were the largest private sector
company first one to get listed uh so
how do you sort of uh now looking back
you find your last five years or post
listing journey and work this I mean
being listed was it some kind of in at
any stage any constant that not being
listed you would have done certain thing
in the last six year differently
so yes it's always easier to be an
unlisted company in terms of operating
Freedom right there's no debating that
but but I think the listing experience
has been very very positive for us while
I say this I think it's been very
positive because
one I think it's built a lot more a
brand awareness for ICC Lombard and that
helps in business you know it's it's not
just for investors but even for our
policyholders I think that helps in our
business
secondly I think all of you have kept us
on our toes and while even earlier we
had investors who are very focused on
how we were running the business now we
have hundreds of thousands of such
investors and you keep us on our toes
which makes us even more efficient
um you know and that's that's at least
we see that as a as a strength as I said
of course there are certain things that
from a disclosure perspective from
approach perspective some of the
unlisted companies do things that we
cannot do and our strategy is in a sense
is public uh people watch our strategies
and and uh and take action so there are
times that we are a bit more guarded
about what we uh say we would have been
even more transparent if all these
companies are well listed uh and that's
the only thing that we kind of guard
against because people abuse the
information asymmetry that is there
yeah so honestly speaking you know the
original act said that after 10 years
all companies should list and in 2015
that was taken away uh I think it's it's
you know it's probably important to
ensure that disclosures are exactly the
same even if uh companies are not listed
in fact one of the things that if you
remember we said at the time of
listening that reserved triangle
disclosure is a vital thing right and we
started disclosing in 2016 before
listing I'm so happy that now that's
coming out and you can watch people's
numbers and figure out what we've been
saying for the last six years
yeah thank you thank you uh now this
sets sort of a context to take this
discussion further now we shall open the
floor for audience questions
hi uh you know we look at uh this is
you look at the retail health insurance
market and uh how it's played out and we
sort of see one player running away with
the retail market rate and when we look
at their claims ratio they are almost
repudiating one in six claims and that
doesn't seem to be impacting either
their growth or their market share in a
meaningful way when you've assessed this
market and you've sort of been measured
about your approach to that market uh
you know what is it that crossed your
mind and you know the way you approach
that market versus the way that player
has approached their Market
uh I think the philosophy that we've had
not for health but for every other
product is that if you want to build an
institution for 100 years
your first priority has to be customer
you have to be customer Centric you have
to really solve for customers issues and
we have an internal joke we've had an
internal joke for even before we were
listed that we don't underwrite at the
time of claims and this is not for help
or anything else so and what that means
is you don't run right at the time of
claims as in when the claim happens that
time you don't start figuring out what
you should have done before what terms
and conditions to apply you know you and
all of those issues to you know reduce
the claim
so with that mindset when you look at
launching products
we would never have a mindset of saying
that let me launch the cheapest product
and I'll manage the claim uh and and
that is a problem that's a challenge but
because it's easy to sell cheap products
right so our positioning as a company
for ever has been we want to sell a
product that is reasonably priced
but the moment of truth in insurance is
claims
and at the time that you need a claim or
you need us to be there we are there you
know Whole Hog uh for you
um as I said at times it's challenging
because it's easy to sell uh you know
cheap products and insurance but our
philosophy and our belief is if you want
to create a long-term Institution
this is the best approach to build a
business you cannot uh follow the
strategy that some companies have
followed and hope that customers will
stay loyal I think the only issue that
we have to Grapple with and by the way
this is work for us for every category
you know including corporates
Cooperative corporate in India is very
sensitive about price but we've kept on
getting market share in corporate
business in spite of the fact that we
are never the cheapest player so so I
think the approach works is our belief
I think the real challenge that we've
had with particularly sahis is the
distribution disadvantage because uh you
know signing up an agent in insurance is
non-trivial you have to go out and meet
10 people you know two of them agreed to
become an agent you go through go
through a testing and a you know
certification process uh training and
certification process you know 50 fail
so out of 10 you end up with one agent
of whom 30 become active so it's a
tremendous you know effort and cost in
building distribution and that when a
computer has an advantage of just
signing up someone else's distributed
that is a real challenge
but be that as as it may be we also have
other advantages which is what we've
been leveraging and over the years we've
kind of uh you know as we see now as you
can see now we are gaining market share
in in retail health
the one reason why we're particularly
you know cautious till 2016 was because
till that time the regulator did not
allow repricing every year
and in health with the 13 14 infection
that we see if you are not allowed
repricing you run a risk of uh you know
kind of either having a very expensive
product at the get go or having losses
in the third year which we had a problem
with so once that changed we then went
in went back into the retail Indie
Market
fish thank you
hi so good evening uh has the company
given any thought of uh procurring the
composite business license uh
so right now there is no point in
debating that because Insurance act has
to change
you know it's anybody's guess when that
will happen
so we are not holding our breath for
that right now
um
we will have to also evaluate how they
come up what kind of construct they come
up with if it comes up with first it has
to come up with and then what construct
uh within a group will they allow
multiple composite licenses
will they allow three different types of
entities all of that we have to debate
and decide and accordingly we will make
up our mind but I think the point that I
was making to Avinash finally at the end
of the day these are very very different
businesses you have to leverage certain
advantages let's say in terms of
distribution but there are certain other
things that you have to really run very
very in a focused Manner
and in a manner that is relevant for
that business what happens for property
PNC Property and Casualty is very
different from what happens in life and
very different from what happens in
health
thank you
uh hi bhargav uh one question we've
discussed issue we've discussed earlier
is inflation in the cost of Health Care
in India
from your business perspective I guess
the annual repricing helps covered that
to some extent
about how much is it a challenge for you
as a business over the longer term to
manage also conversely does it sort of
perversely help you help the propensity
to buy health insurance as inflation
picks up customer awareness about how
you know buying Insurance help it so I
guess it works both sides but how do you
challenge how do you manage that
challenge over the longer term I think
that's a great question and and I think
there's it's yes to both but obviously
you have to find the right balance uh
Healthcare inflation and the fact that
you end up spending seven eight lakhs if
you go to a hospital in the big cities
in India creates the awareness and the
and this and the the sense of need to
buy insurance
but in the long term if cost of
healthcare keeps going up cost of the
premium keeps going up it will have an
impact in terms of penetration because
you can maybe touch the top 10 15
percent of the population you can't go
below that at one level
and the second more uh social or more at
a country level the issue that we have
to you have to deal with is that we
don't want at least personally I
wouldn't want to see India go the U.S
way where let's say 19 percent of the
GDP is in healthcare cost I think that
bears a tremendous cost uh you know to
the economy so you have to find the
right balance
I think there's a lot of work that is
happening to find what the middle ground
um
one of course you know the bottom 45 50
of the population there is a there is a
model that has already been rolled out
gradually people will be more aware and
you know hopefully consume that
insurance
the missing middle there is a lot of
work that is going on uh largely
encouraged by the policy makers Ida as
an industry we are obviously Keen to
solve that problem
and we are aware that to solve to crack
that code we have to find
affordable cost of care which is not in
really in our control it's something
that we have to do as a as a partnership
model with with healthcare providers
lastly even for the top 10 15 percent
this kind of inflation is not great and
I think there's a possibility there's a
lot of work going on in terms of the
again with the blessings of the
regulator in terms of the industry to
come together and at least control the
fraud waste and abuse that is happening
which can be defended by no one uh and
that's one Journey that is that some
work is happening there's some work
happening on building a health claim
exchange so that transactions are
digital and at least that cost of uh
service comes down and once it is a once
it's digital then you can also run a lot
more analytics around some of the issues
that are happening iib has started
coming out with some data across
industry data cross company data on uh
fraud which I think has really helped
the banking industry the credit bureaus
similar thought on the insurance side so
rather than say that you know cost has
to be kept at this level we are trying
to focus on the fraud waste and abuse
and through that process reduce the
inflation of insurance
thank you
hi good evening uh
with the new regulations with regard to
commission and expense management by the
regulator right like what kind of impact
do you see a on you know on Lombard and
B on the industry as a whole
thank you so uh if you see global
benchmarks
in no developed markets do you even see
expensive management for GI you know it
may make sense for uh savings products
but not for GI in India we had expensive
management we had sub limits of
commission within each product we had
further sub limits of I mean this is
almost impossible for anyone to manage
So to that extent this really eases up
our operations purely from a ease of you
know doing business it's great but even
this if you look at Global benchmarking
if you talk to let's say the global
analysts or if you talk to a global
rating agency they'll be surpassed to
hear what is this um right as I said let
it be for the time being but um actually
really helps us not just from operations
perspective but
what the regulator has said that anyone
which is who is more than 30 or more
than 35 percent for a for a sahi should
have a Glide path or has a Glide path of
bringing it under control in the next
three years and we've seen you almost
two thirds of the companies are above
that limit
so if that happens if they actually
bring it down so it's it depends on how
much the regulator enforces the new
regulation that they've put in and we
have to watch for that I think the first
quarter numbers for all companies will
be out and then we'll see what the um
numbers are for them and then we'll see
what the regulator does if that happens
I think it will help companies which are
lower than you know 30 um or lower than
35 um
from our perspective we have cushion but
that doesn't mean that we unnecessarily
increase our spins simply because the
pressure to increase pens will come down
if others are also bringing down uh and
secondly we obviously have an objective
of combined ratio so that's something
that we want to manage so in the long
term you know the sense that we have is
that the regulator is very keen to
reduce the overall distribution cost for
the sector without bringing in some kind
of a regulatory mandate saying that this
is it so that they're doing it in my
opinion the right way setting an overall
framework and nudging the industry to
reduce the distribution cost
and you know initially 30 percent but
we'll see if if it comes down we will uh
see how others what they do there at the
next level lastly I think companies with
multiple lines of businesses we have an
advantage because we can kind of manage
the book across different lines of
business in terms of the uh limits that
we have across different lines plus
scale Advantage definitely is something
that we have so all in all we are very
very uh I mean this has been asked for
the industry for a long long time so we
are very happy this has come or from an
ease of doing business perspective as
also uh the flexibility in managing our
business in a meaningful Manner and
hopefully in the longer term the
solution cost comes down
so we have seen in our business a
broking business technology leveraged
and commission rates have continuously
kept on going down
now similarly have you been able to
leverage your technology whereby the
premium that you collect here on motor
insurance for example have you been able
to gather more data Etc and ensure that
for the same Capital value what premiums
or insurance premiums we were charging
say 10 years ago has it come down or
have you made that effort or something
like that has happened
if you take a Long View and let's take
2008 to 2023 15 years Long View right
um
you'll see that
Insurance the uh the inflation is
actually it's probably deflationary in
certain product ranges so all PNC ranges
prices lower today than what it is in
2008.
um largely driven by competition but
I'll give you let's say another data
point for you to consume so ice is a
Lombard
um let's say in 2008 we
um were writing about 3.2 million
policies at that year last year we wrote
32 million policies about 10x right if
you Compound on a cagr of 16 percent
if you look at our gwp growth uh in the
same periods about 13 and a half percent
0wp growth so obviously the the business
has got more granularized and that's
what has happened for us
if you look at our head count all our
employee plus all the ft's for example
you know staff whose kind of Outsource
staff who work for us that number is
down by about 25 percent from that time
down by 25 percent
if you look at our profit kagger in this
period it's about 20 profit so Top Line
cargo of 13 profit kegger of 20 in an
industry where from 2008 to 2023
industry profit have actually come down
for industry profit has been lower in
2023 than what it was in 2008. so the
answer is obviously yes all of this is
because of Technology now
maybe till about 2017 the focus was in
automation you know cost reduction
convenience you know Drive digitization
of policies uh we reached about 97
percent of our policies we don't see
paper today so that was still 2016-17
since then the focus has been in terms
of you know AI ml you know you know
analytics better propensity models so
that's what we've been doing so I would
say the last four or five years lot of
work has happened on that area
particularly in the area of fraud
underwriting claims processing uh you
know where we're using lot of these uh
machine learning models to make it even
more effective not just efficient but
also more effective in terms of the
quality of decisions that we're taking
so the answer is absolutely yes uh
significant reduction in in cost of
service as also ticket size and you know
premium per policy over these years in
spite of that we've had a pretty decent
run in terms of profit kagger
thank you
so
um are there any big untapped segments
in GI which you see in other parts of
the world which probably has not come to
India and you think that it could there
is a scope for that to happen so there
are untapped segments for example home
you know we just talked about so if you
look at the number of uh pakka houses in
India and look at even a 10 000 rupee
policy that's a 60 to 70 000 crore
Market uh you know even if you get to 20
of penetration you're talking about
another 15 000 crore market so there's a
massive opportunity in new areas but
forget new areas if you look at motor
insurance we've talked about this 50 of
the motor vehicles on this country in
this country drive without insurance SME
penetration about single digit four to
five percent
um
large corporates they you know under
insurance so every time there's a claim
we evaluate and we realize that whatever
is the sum insured they've Not Taken
full some insured so under insurance or
business Interruption policies very
common everywhere in the world Indians
don't Indian corporates don't take it
except for the some corporates
non-damaged UI no one's no one takes in
India
so even in existing category is health I
mean we are still talking about top 10
percent of the population who has a
proper health insurance so uh by the way
in health uh we are only talking about
ipd hospitalization which is
largely about 30 30 33 of the Total
Health Care spends 65 which is
outpatient not covered everywhere in the
world is covered right so in existing
categories there is a massive amount of
uh you know coverage cap that still
exists uh in terms of policy or in terms
of adequacy of cover that people buy and
then there are these new uh you know
areas that we are talking about are not
new but areas where other in other
markets we see significant penetration
so our sense is that and and you see the
numbers right our insurance density is
one tenth of China
forget us or forget Europe I mean
they're like you know you know a few
hundred times more so I think there's a
massive under penetration India will
never go to those levels of course
you're in a different Market but even to
reach you know let's say a Chinese
numbers we have a longer you know path
of growth for ourselves
so when it comes to home insurance is it
is it that the consumers assume that the
odds are something going wrong are
infinitely small which is why they don't
take out insurance or is it a cost of
insurance and which is why you want to
tweak in regulatory policies
so I think there is also let us say
motor insurance right ah I think people
think that they can get away with
breaking the law in India that's always
the worry that you know deterrence is
very poor
um
also they may think that you know my two
wheeler three four-year-old
you know I'll get it repaired on the
roadside doesn't matter I'll manage it
uh accident is not that frequent
um
so that's a mindset issue which is
changing and the same mindset we saw in
health uh 10 years back that's changing
so and if you see Global Studies uh
Sigma does a Swiss Swiss trees body
called they have a body called Sigma
their Sigma report they show data across
economies where the GI penetration curve
is a hockey you know s-shaped curve
which picks up a 2000 to 2500 per capita
then goes up like this and then flattens
at I think about ten thousand dollar per
capita so this is we are at that cusp it
it has to happen because you know when
an economy grows first you think about
savings then you think about investment
then you think of assets you know buying
homes buying you know uh two wheelers
then you think about you know protecting
those it's a natural progression if you
look at all other Financial Services
categories GI innocence comes last in
terms of priority
and last question so you've got this
baksha hathway does this super cat which
is writing against earthquake and from
falling indices 10 years out will that
part always be an entrepreneurial setup
or
can can those kind of insurance get
institutionalized
no it's you know if you look at the
Players writing some of those exposures
uh include some of the big Global
reinsurers right I mean these are
institutional players I mean municry or
even Berkshire you know they're not a
you know they're in now institutions
it's an insurance Market because you
need very very Deep Pockets to write
those exposures and written it on on
your net and you need to have
diversification across the globe
you cannot write those kind of exposures
in India because one year I mean sitting
in India writing for India it's a
massive risk so for us it makes more
sense to protect our balance sheet
taking those range cat regions for
example so that uh massive events happen
we don't have a have a big hit so for
example you know last two quarters
there's been cats in India right it it
may have some it will have some impact
couple of percentage point in our
combined but it's not going to blow or
balance it by any stretch of imagination
thank you
so two question I have clubbed because I
was expecting that to come from
audiences that one in a market where the
players are obsessed with growth and
customer are very very price sensitive
and that is what sort of a gives a rise
to you know I would say a bit of a
predatory b2c Brokers under different
names uh you have been someone who sort
of stayed away from this
in a kind of a commoditized market so I
mean if you can just sort of explain uh
what's your thought process behind this
I mean in a growth obsessed a
competition and you know a value
conscious customer how did you sort of
uh uh executed your thought process
behind staying away from this so that's
one and added to that because you were
talking about a motor I mean in India
one of part of course the prices have
come down but the prices are still
particularly for you the cost is high
because uh your I mean the claims
management or claim uh servicing is done
lastly by the OEM LED garages
and it's a kind of a no secret the kind
of cost they sort of or the inflated
bill that comes do you see sort of a
solution of that problem in your future
yeah the second one uh
if you have to find a solution there
would be some amount of intervention by
the regulator otherwise it may be very
difficult to find a solution
um
but there's you know you can never say
no it's highly possible that something
something like that will happen the
second thing there on motor is that for
example for us the percentage of digital
and our agency Channel Source business
is increasing day by day and there you
know let's say when we started our PPN
Journey PPN is preferred payment Network
garages where we divert our customers to
those garages
we provide service guarantee we provide
you know claims experience guarantee
Parts Etc all of that we provide and we
still see some savings that percentage
has been increasing
year on year so now it's you know in the
mid 60s in certain months we reach even
higher numbers so all of that actually
brings down the cost of claim and if you
see I think the you know the first
quarter some of the numbers that we
talked about some of these things are
playing out
but purely OEM sourced OEM service the
point that you're making is valid but
usually in these things you know as you
know the systemic pressure one day comes
in and you know these things get get
moderated my sense it will happen even
in India I can't predict when
your larger question of managing for a
balance
um you see at least our view is that at
the end of the day uh for a large brand
which positions itself on service
competing on price uh on a on a digital
platform doesn't make sense number one
number two uh you don't own the customer
there's a lot of churn with those
customers uh it makes it made much more
sense to build or spend the same amount
of money building your own d2c model
with your own own channel and we invest
that for our digital you know our
digital business or website as also our
mobile app right and if you've seen the
impact that we've had on the mobile app
it's really three four years it's a new
mobile app earlier the app was a sales
app 2019 we launched our service app
that's doing in our opinion brilliantly
well and you know month on month we are
seeing super attraction so we would
rather spend the money as a Big Brand I
mean if you were a small brand I would
have been there but as a Big Brand it
makes more sense to uh build your direct
connect with custom was and lastly you
know chasing growth at the cost of
profits
we've never done that and I think we've
done okay as I said you know at the end
of the day finally you it's not only Top
Line growth that is matters it's also
bottom line growth and I give the
numbers for the last 15 years 20 kagger
in terms of profits
back in 2008 we had we probably made 100
crores of profit last time we made 700
closer profits
thank you uh we can take one more
audience question or which
yeah so
ird
idea with the implementation of IRS from
possibly from 525 so what kind of impact
is it expected to have on the industry
as
so multiple levels I think your exact uh
model uh will be decided as we go along
but there would be impact both on the
asset side as also on the liability side
um on the investment side there would be
impact on Mark to Market and how we
account for it uh on the on the
liability side there will be a huge
impact potentially let me explain this
in two minutes uh so that you get the
grasp of what we are talking about so in
in India the third party claim duration
is very long right so on an average it's
about six years by our estimate we hold
a reserve which is on a inflated
nominally inflated basis so if it's a
hundred thousand rupee claim today if
you think it's a 12 percent inflation
then we hold 200 000 rupees on that
Reserve because it will be paid six
years later now globally or under IFRS
that should be discounted by you know
risk risk-free rate and brought into
present value
in which case we should be holding let's
say about 140 000 so that means sixty
thousand rupees will be released and in
fact this quarter we put out the number
in terms of what happens to a combined
ratio as a company if you followed IFRS
only on this account because everything
else is not not finalized so our
combined ratio improves by about four
percent if you follow Global standards
uh on and that's why we've always been
saying that Indian combined ratio is not
comparable with the combined ratio
elsewhere now what happens at that point
in time in terms of whether this one
time
upside for the industry is it going to
be parked in the balance sheet will you
flow through the p l all of those are
issues that will be uh addressed but I
think a lot more uh comparability of
account accounting will happen uh you
will be you'll be able to Benchmark
numbers vis-a-vis other other markets
companies which are holding low
inflation let's say in that example that
I gave of 12 percent inflation if I'm
holding five percent inflation
I may have a problem and some companies
We Believe do hold very low inflation
number so so those things I think there
will be a lot more a lot greater
comparability and transparency
so with this we should close this
session thank you Vargo thank you a lot
that was I mean very insightful talk and
definitely provided a lot about I mean a
lot of understanding about the past and
probably the future of the sector thank
you thank you having a witness thank you
[Music]
thank you